Mohsen Saeidi

CONTACT E-mail: saeidi.mhsn@gmail.com

INFORMATION Skype: sd.mohsen

Webpage: mohsensaeidi.ir



PROFESSIONAL

SUMMARY

Versatile Java Developer experienced with the full software development lifecycle and comfortable working within Agile development frameworks. Organized and hardworking team player with strong verbal and written communication skills. Prepared to bring 9 years of related experience to a challenging position.

EXPERIENCE

Software engineer at CodeitLabs, Munich

Java Technical Lead at Dotin, Tehran, Iran

Senior Java Developer and Lead Architect at Limoome

Jun 2017 – Jan 2020

Jun 2016 – May 2017

Software Engineer at Fanap

Jun 2013 – May 2017

Software Engineer at Karnik System Shargh

Aug 2012 – Jun 2013

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Standard Skills

- Core Java Experience
- Software Development Lifecycle
- System Design & Software Architecture
- Automating Unit Testing
- J2EE Architecture Specialist
- Linux Administration
- Database Design
- Excellent Communication Skills
- Excellent Problem-Solving Abilities
- Code Review
- Enterprise Applications
- New Employee Mentoring
- Planning & Implementation
- Java 11
- C, C++, C#
- Python
- Html, CSS, JavaScript
- Spring Framework
- ORM, Hibernate/JPA
- JSF, MyFaces, PrimeFaces, JSP
- Rest, Soap Services
- React, Redux, Nodejs
- Shell Script
- ELK Stack

Programming Methodologies

- Agile Development Methodology
- DevOps Principles
- CI/CD
- Aspect Oriented Programming
- Bug Tracking, Troubleshooting
- Micro Service Architecture

Tools & Applications

- Maven, Gradle
- Apache2, Tomcat
- Hadoop, Spark
- Git. SVN
- CAS/SSO
- SSL Certificate Installation
- RabbitMQ

Database Systems

- Oracle DB
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Redis

EDUCATION

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Master of Science in Computer Networks Sep 2016 – Jun 2019 University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran Bachelor of Science in Information Technology **Sep 2011 – Aug 2015** Hatef High School, Tehran, Iran Diploma in Physics and Mathematics discipline Sep 2007 - Aug 2011 Stack Overflow more than 4k reputation (https://bit.ly/2UCxsy0). SAP Certified Development Professional - SAP Commerce Cloud 1905 Developer issued by SAP SE (https://bit.ly/3utOYGU) 16th position in Iran university entrance MSc exam of Computer Engineering. 2nd position in Iran RoboCup 2D Soccer Simulation competitions 2009. 2nd position in Iran Robotics Festival Junior 2D Soccer Simulation League 2009. **English:** Professional working proficiency Persian: Native **German:** Elementary proficiency(A2) **Arabic:** Elementary proficiency Manor: Manor is a Swiss department store chain with its headquarters in Basel. It is Switzerland's largest department-store chain. (https://www.manor.ch) Technologies: SAP Hybris Commerce 1905, Java11, Spring framework, JSP, MySQL database, Maven/Gradle, Splunk, REST and SOAP service, Git. Duties: As an SAP Commerce developer my major duties are mapping client business requirements, processes and objectives then develops necessary modules. **Dotin Core Insurance:** A general insurance system solution web enterprise that

HONORS AND

AWARDS

LANGUAGE

SKILLS

NOTABLE

PROJECTS

consists of many modules as insurance setup, servicing and quotation, financial and accounting, claim processing and recovery(https://core.pasargadinsurance.ir). Technologies: J2EE, CAS/SSO, Spring framework, Hibernate, Servelts/JSP, JSF,

Oracle database, Tomcat, Maven, SOAP, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Git, lots more. Duties: Java technical lead. My major duties were lead in software design, secure quality of team deliverables, Implementing the best practices and coding standards of the project and also code review and mentoring team members.

Recommendation System Based on Network Coding: My M.Sc. Project which using network coding algorithms to improve performance of map reduce frameworks and implemented on recommendation systems.

Technologies: Hadoop, Spark, Java, Python, AWS, Star Cluster.

Limoome: A Telegram bot that get all medical information from users and generates a diet based on their metabolism(https://limoome.com/).

Technologies: Java, Spring boot, Hibernate/JPA, PostgreSQL, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Spring MVC, AWS, Heroku, Office 365, Git.

Duties: Completely done by myself.

<u>Ghasedak Book</u>: A desktop application for book stores that include all steps from inventory management to sale invoice and other modules.

Technologies: C#, NHibernate, Microsoft SQL Server, Crystal Reports.

Duties: Completely done by myself.

<u>**Dotin POS Driver:**</u> A driver for Dotin POS that provides users to use their debit card without entering price or any other information.

Technologies: Java Applet, JQuery, Node.js, nssm, Servlets/JSP, CSS, HTML.

Duties: Completely done by myself.